Alex J. Broderick

2205 Rosewood Ave, Richmond, VA 23220 | C: 518-788-8014 | alexjbroderick@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Analyst and Business Support Professional of seven years working with a broad range of clientele. With experience in managing financial and administrative profiles, can bring a creative new outlook to existing organizational structure.

Accomplishments

Report Development & Automation – Blending datasets to create and standardize data tables & reports for internal users containing micro and macro level of detail for further analysis

Project Management – Leading team of employees to ensure accurate and timely statements for business use internally and externally

Impact Maker of the Year 2019 - Award determined by McKesson Medical Surgical Leadership for contributions to organization's annual goals

Experience

McKesson Medical Surgical

Richmond, VA

Merchandising Program Manager

06/2021 to Present

- Oversight of sales programs with incentives to grow revenue and profit
- Collaborate with IT to implement reporting for use by Sales Team
- Serve as subject matter expert for market data

Senior Category Analyst

09/2017 to 06/2021

- Collaborate with Category Management to investigate financial trends
- Compile data to assist with development, implementation and tracking of new products

Data Visualization Analyst

07/2016 to 09/2017

- Maintain Tableau server and reports through monthly refreshes and user governance
- Lead training sessions with teams to teach about existing and new reports

Virginia Premier Health Plan, Inc.

Richmond, VA

Business Analyst III

05/2016 to 07/2016

- Work with external clients to determine requirements for operational efficiency
- Assist in implementation of new partnerships with external vendors across Virginia

Business Analyst II

03/2015 to 05/2016

- Creation and implementation of reports to aid in internal processes
- Collaborate with internal teams within finance to develop targets for government reporting

Education

Master of Business Administration: Technology Management & Quality and Applied Statistics

2014

2013

2017

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Science: *Economics* Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Certifications

Post Baccalaureate: Lean Six Sigma Black Belt Certification

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Tableau: Desktop Certified Associate

2017

Skills

Technical: Query Writing, Project Management, Report Creation, Automation, Forecasting Modeling

Software: SQL, Oracle, Tableau, PowerBI, Python, ArcGIS, Alteryx, Advanced Excel